Krishna Singh

ksingh@gmail.com (925) 555-1187 Davis, CA

Advocate for underserved populations working to develop programming to support marginalized communities. Experienced educator at multiple levels highlighting individual contribution and employing active learning and learner-centered pedagogy. Dedicated to advancing organizational diversity, equity, and inclusion approaches.

EXPERIENCE

Researcher, Department of Cultural Studies, University of California, Davis

9/2019 - 6/2024

- Assessed student academic-relevant variables, such as sense of belonging, by conducting observations and surveys related to cultural identity and awareness in various settings
- Developed educational materials to advance diversity, equity, and inclusion initiatives
- Trained and supervised 10 research assistants on protocols and cultural competency in person and virtually
- Presented summary of studies and key findings at international research conferences
- Published peer-reviewed articles detailing research findings, implications, and suggestions for intervention

Graduate Peer Advisor, UC Davis Career Center, University of California, Davis

9/2023 - 6/2024

- Advised graduate students individually and through group workshops regarding career exploration
- Conducted advising sessions and workshops both in-person and virtually
- Designed tailored and inclusive workshop content
- Reviewed and provided individualized feedback on application documents

Associate Instructor, Department of English, University of California, Davis

9/2021 - 6/2023

- Taught 30 undergraduate students critical thinking and rhetoric
- Employed various pedagogy to ensure compatibility with different learning styles
- Graded essays and provided feedback to improve student writing

Tutor, Learning Resource Center, American River College, Sacramento, CA

8/2017 - 6/2019

- Developed tutoring materials to aid students in English language learning
- Provided individualized support for over 30 undergraduate students from various backgrounds

Barista, Starbucks, Fair Oaks, CA

1/2011 - 7/2016

- Actively listened to customer to ensure accuracy of order and provide a pleasant experience
- Trained new employees on company procedures and provided ongoing mentorship
- Resolved customer complaints quickly and efficiently

EDUCATION

PhD in Cultural Studies, University of California, Davis

September 2024

MA in Education, California State University, Sacramento

May 2019

BA in History, California State University, Sacramento

May 2016